Yeah, we got some uh listener questions
that we're going to run through now. Uh
I'm going to try and read them in
Chinese to see how far I get and then
Suze is going to take over and read them
properly in Chinese.
>> Yeah, Rick's been learning Chinese for
quite a while now, right?
>> Over 3 years now and I'd like to say
that my reading is better than my
speaking or listening, but I don't know.
I think I it's fading a little bit now.
I haven't done that much in the past
month, but I'm going to get back on it
>> How are you learning?
>> Mostly um
different apps and stuff on YouTube,
which is quite useful. Um really I could
I could be learning a lot. I could be
putting a lot more effort into it, but I
do I don't know. It's still fun for me,
so I like to I like to do it still.
>> Yeah, I think if you enjoy it, the fact
that you've kept it up this long is like
quite impressive. And you said you can
recognize a lot of characters, right?
>> I I can recognize a fair few. Yeah,
yeah. Um
it's tricky sometimes. Well, let's see
how far I get. Okay, so the first
question is, is memorization considered
a bad thing in Western education? And I
can read Zai Xi Fang Shu something Li
Jiao Jiao Li. That's teaching, I guess.
The Western Oh, Western education That's
Western education. Yeah, education.
Can't read those two and then it says
Jun De Fang. Is that No, that's not
Fang. Is it Fang?
>> Uh Jun De Fang Bei.
>> Do you know Bei? It's like passive.
>> Bei The passive character, yeah.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Uh Jun De Bei something something Shi Bu
Hao De something something Fang Fang Shi
something.
>> Ma. Yeah, so this is in traditional
Chinese, so I guess you don't know the
Ma in traditional Chinese.
>> No, I don't. Yeah, that This is another
problem is that I can't recognize all of
these are different, so uh
>> It doesn't take too long, though. If you
learn traditional it like maybe a couple
months you start to see the patterns and
cuz most of them are the same. You just
get a few that are different. No, the
one that you didn't know there was quite
difficult. Uh Bei Song is like
memorization.
>> Oh, I would never have got that. Uh
sorry to our listeners, by the way. That
was That was a terrible uh
>> [laughter]
>> That was absolutely terrible.
>> No, it's pretty good. You can clearly
tell that you've learned. You wouldn't
be to do that if you hadn't been
learning.
>> I think as long as people know that I
know some Chinese, that's what matters
to me really. So I can like show off a
little bit.
>> [laughter]
>> They know that I know a bit. That's
fine. Anyway, Susie, take it away and
read it properly in Chinese.
There we go. Beautiful.
>> [music]